<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Based Cooking</title><link>https://based.cooking/tags/asian/</link><description>Recent content in asian on Based Cooking</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://based.cooking/tags/asian/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Chicken Satay with Peanut Sauce</title><link>https://based.cooking/chicken-satay/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://based.cooking/chicken-satay/</guid><description>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>â²ï¸ Prep time: 10 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ðŸ³ Cook time: 15 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ðŸ½ï¸ Servings: 4&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>2 lbs boneless chicken breast or thigh&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1.5 tbsp oyster sauce&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 tbsp ground tumeric&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 tbsp sugar&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 tbsp coconut milk&lt;/li>
&lt;li>3 tbsp peanut butter (creamy)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 tbsp massaman curry paste&lt;/li>
&lt;li>water to thin peanut sauce&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Cut the chicken into 1/2 inch thick strips.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Mix chicken with oyster sauce, tumeric, 1 tbsp sugar and coconut milk. Allow chicken to marinade for at least an hour.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Optionally, you can skewer the meat with wooden skewers.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Grill chicken until cooked through.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Mix peanut butter, 1 tbsp sugar and curry paste together in a small saucepan. Add enough water to thin to a thick sauce.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cook for 1-2 min stirring frequently.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Serve chicken with peanut sauce for dipping.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Yibin Burning Noodles</title><link>https://based.cooking/yibin-burning-noodles/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://based.cooking/yibin-burning-noodles/</guid><description>&lt;p>This is a dry noodle dish from the town of Yibin in Sichuan, China.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="yibin-chili-oil">Yibin Chili Oil&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Sichuan ground chilies, 1/3 cup&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Roasted rapeseed oil (caizi you) or Chinese peanut oil, 2/3 cup&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Peeled and smashed ginger, 2 inches&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cassia bark (or cinnamon stick), 2 inches&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Star anise, 2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Chinese black cardamom (optional), 1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Sichuan peppercorn, 1 tsp&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Roughly chopped walnut pieces, 2 tbsp&lt;/li>
&lt;li>High-quality melted pork lard, 1/3 cup&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="noodles">Noodles&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Fresh alkaline noodles, 150g&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Yibin Chili Oil&lt;/strong>, 2 tbsp&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Light soy sauce, 1 tbsp&lt;/li>
&lt;li>White sesame oil, 1 tbsp&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Toasted yacai, 2 tbsp&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Mixed toasted crushed peanuts/sesame, 2 tbsp&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Sliced scallion greens, 2 tbsp&lt;/li>
&lt;li>MSG, 1/4 tbsp&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="yibin-chili-oil-1">Yibin Chili Oil&lt;/h3>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Add ground chilies to a heat-proof jar or bowl.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Heat rapeseed oil (or Chinese peanut oil) over medium heat until lightly smoking at approximately 230Â°C for 2 minutes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Turn off heat and let oil cool down to about 150Â°C.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Turn flame back to medium and add ginger, cassia bark, star anise, black cardamom, Sichuan peppercorn and chopped walnut pieces.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Simmer for 10 minutes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Ensure the oil is approximately 150Â°C&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Pour oil through a strainer onto the ground chilies.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Stir thoroughly.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add the melted pork lard.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Stir thoroughly.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="noodles-1">Noodles&lt;/h3>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Boil the noodles for approximately 1 minute (slightly past al dente).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Strain the noodles thoroughly.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add all the sauces and oils from the &amp;ldquo;Noodles&amp;rdquo; ingredients list.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Top with the remaining ingredients.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Asian Style Chicken with Sticky Sauce</title><link>https://based.cooking/asian-style-chicken-sticky-sauce/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://based.cooking/asian-style-chicken-sticky-sauce/</guid><description>&lt;p>Asian style crispy coated chicken with sweetish sauce recipe. Served with boiled rice.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://based.cooking/pix/asian-style-chicken-sticky-sauce.webp" alt="Asian Style Chicken with Sticky Sauce">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="chicken-with-crispy-coating">Chicken with crispy coating&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Around 14 ounces or 400 grams of chicken breast&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 Egg&lt;/li>
&lt;li>3 tbsp of cornflour&lt;/li>
&lt;li>10 tbsp all-purpose flour&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/2 tsp garlic powder&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 tsp paprika powder&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Around 5 tbsp of sesame oil for frying the chicken&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="sauce">Sauce&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>1 tbsp sesame oil&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 garlic cloves, mashed to paste.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 tbsp Chinese rice vinegar or alternatively white wine vinegar&lt;/li>
&lt;li>3 tbsp honey&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 tbsp ketchup&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 tbsp brown sugar&lt;/li>
&lt;li>4 tbsp soy sauce&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Prepare the sauce by mixing the ingredients together in a bowl.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cut the chicken into bite sized pieces.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Place all-purpose flour in a shallow bowl. Mix in garlic powder as well as salt and pepper, 1/2 tsp each.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Place lightly beaten egg in another shallow bowl.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Coat the chicken in corn flour, dip it in egg and finally coat with seasoned all purpose-flour.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Heat a good amount of oil on a pan to fry the chicken in. The oil should be hot enough so that the chicken sizzles when placed in the pan. You may want to do this in a couple of batches depending on the size of your pan.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fry until chicken is cooked and has a nice golden-brownish coating.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Pour out excess oil, put the sauce in and mix to coat the chicken. Or place the chicken in a bowl with kitchen towels and do another batch.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Let the sauce bubble for one or two minutes and you&amp;rsquo;re done.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Serve with boiled rice.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Egg Roll in a Bowl</title><link>https://based.cooking/eggroll-in-a-bowl/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://based.cooking/eggroll-in-a-bowl/</guid><description>&lt;p>Egg rolls, but, you know, in a bowl.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>â²ï¸ Prep time: 10 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ðŸ³ Cook time: 15 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ðŸ½ï¸ Servings: 2&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>1 pound ground turkey&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 bag coleslaw mix&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 small onion&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2-3 cloves of garlic&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 tbsp fresh ginger&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/4 cup Hoisin sauce&lt;/li>
&lt;li>soy sauce&lt;/li>
&lt;li>sesame oil&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Grate or mince ginger finely. Process with the garlic cloves by grinding with salt under the edge of a knife. Finely mince the onion. &lt;strong>Optional&lt;/strong> Marinade the ground turkey in 2 Tbsp of soy sauce and 1 tsp baking soda for 15 minutes to improve browning.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>In a hot wok or skillet add a few tablespoons of cooking oil, preferably peanut, and a tsp of sesame oil. Add the ground turkey and cook until no longer raw seasoning with soy sauce.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Add the onion and cook until translucent and the meat is nicely browned. Add in the garlic and ginger mixture and cook for approximately 1 minute or until fragrant ensuring not to burn the garlic.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Add in the coleslaw mix and season with more soy sauce. Cook until the cabbage is just softened. Add 1/4 cup of hoisin sauce and stir to combine. Check seasoning and add salt to taste. Serve in a bowl with sweet chili sauce and green onions.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Stir Fried Chicken with an Orange Sauce</title><link>https://based.cooking/stir-fried-chicken-with-an-orange-sauce/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://based.cooking/stir-fried-chicken-with-an-orange-sauce/</guid><description>&lt;p>I could have called this Orange Chicken but I feel like some people wouldn&amp;rsquo;t classify my recipe that way.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Chicken (a pound or two)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Oranges&lt;/li>
&lt;li>An Onion&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Two Red Bell Peppers&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Soy Sauce&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Honey&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Butter&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Flour&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Chop your onion and red bell peppers into small bits and throw them in a large frying pan to cook with a pat of butter, stirring occasionally.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Chop your chicken into small bite sized pieces, add them to your pan once your onions begin to become translucent. Stir occasionally.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>If you have something to zest your oranges with add some zest to the ingredients in your pan (if you don&amp;rsquo;t have a zesting thing don&amp;rsquo;t worry about it).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>While your chicken is cooking hand squeeze the juice out of your oranges into a bowl, I will usually use the juice of five oranges but three or four might be enough.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Once your chicken is cooked pour your freshly squeezed orange juice into your pan, then pour in some soy sauce (you want your orange juice to soy sauce ratio to be about 3:1, use your best judgment on how much to pour in). Add honey (use as much as you want, I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t use less than two tablespoons though) and stir. Turn the stove to medium-high.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Let that sit for a few minutes to let the flavors get to know each other a bit, then stir in a few spoonfuls of flour to thicken the sauce.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Once the sauce has reached your preferred level of thickness take it off the heat. Serve over rice.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Broccoli with Ginger and Garlic Sauce</title><link>https://based.cooking/ginger-garlic-broccoli/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://based.cooking/ginger-garlic-broccoli/</guid><description>&lt;p>Asian inspired broccoli dish with tasty sauce. Sauce can be used for all kinds of Asian inspired sauted vegetables.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>â²ï¸ Prep time: 5 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ðŸ³ Cook time: 10 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ðŸ½ï¸ Servings: 2&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>1-2 Broccoli (fresh best, frozen works too)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Minced garlic (1 tablespoon)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Minced ginger (1 tablespoon)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Sherry or regular white wine (you cook with what you drink with!) (1 tablespoon)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Soy sauce (1-2 tablespoon)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Cut broccoli into little flourettes (hold the broccoli upside down and cut around the stem with a pairing knife)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fill your pan (or wok) around half inch (1.57cm) with water and bring to a rapid boil.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Put broccoli in and steam with lid on for approx. 3 minutes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Drain broccoli and wipe pan dry.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>One teaspoon of oil and saute garlic and ginger (use sesame seed oil for Asian touch, but neutral or olive oil works well too).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Deglaze with sherry, put half a cup (approx 120 ml) of warm water or chicken stock. Reduce on medium-high heat.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Stir in soy sauce, brown sugar and lemon juice to your taste.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Thicken sauce with corn starch.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Put dry cooked broccoli back in and saute for very short time (you want it nice and crunchy).&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item></channel></rss>