<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Based Cooking</title><link>https://based.cooking/tags/milk/</link><description>Recent content in milk on Based Cooking</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://based.cooking/tags/milk/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Dulce de Leche</title><link>https://based.cooking/dulce-de-leche/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://based.cooking/dulce-de-leche/</guid><description>&lt;p>Delicious milk toffee used on desserts or as a spread. Substitute for Nootella or similar &amp;ldquo;food&amp;rdquo;. It is very demanding, so i only recommend you make it if you either can&amp;rsquo;t buy industrial dulce de leche (It will be way more natural than other sweets anyway), or have the time and interest to go through the process. It can be made more easily with sweetened condensed milk, but if you have access to it, you can get DDL anyways.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>â²ï¸ Prep time: 5 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ðŸ³ Cook time: 3 hours&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ðŸ½ï¸ Servings: An average-sized mason jar.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>1 liter of milk.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>350 grams of sugar.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Half a teaspoon of baking soda.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>A vanilla bean, or essence (Optional)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Two glass marbles (Optional, but it is a traditional way to prevent sticking, and they will not break in the process.)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Heat all ingredients in a pan (with the marbles, if you want,) on a medium-heat stove, constantly mixing with a wooden spoon.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Once the sugar dissolves, set heat to very low, and keep mixing once in a while for approximately two hours. It should not boil, if it happens, set it aside, keep mixing and once the temperature lowers put it back on the heat.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Once the preparation gets thicker, be more careful and mix it more frequently so that it does not stick (and burn)
and lumps do not form.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Once you get a consistency similar to that of a custard, set it aside and keep mixind for 10 minutes, until it gets
cold and thickens a bit more. If you put a spoon inside, pass your finger in the middle and it does not unite anymore, it is done.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Once cold, put it on a glass jar and leave it in the fridge, or sterilize it.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Potato Soup</title><link>https://based.cooking/potato-soup/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://based.cooking/potato-soup/</guid><description>&lt;p>Serves many people or one person for many days.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Potatoes (yellow or brown), I don&amp;rsquo;t count but 10+&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Butter, a stick or two&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Whole Milk&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Garlic&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cheese (optional)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Onion Greens (optional)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Sour Cream (optional)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Bake the potatoes at 450Â° for about an hour.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Take them out and leave them to cool for a good 10 minutes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Begin heating up a big pot to about medium temperature, and put the butter in to melt.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cut the potatoes in half and scoop them directly into the pot.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Once you are finished with that, begin mashing them until they are a nice mashed-potato-like consistency.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add milk little by little, stirring as you go, until you reach the desired consistency. I usually use half a gallon or so.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Shred cheese into the soup. Then add garlic, salt, pepper, cayenne, onion greens, and anything else you can think of.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Let the soup reach a boil, stirring constantly. Remove from heat and serve.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I usually eat it with sour cream mixed in to cool it down and get that extra dairy in.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Tanzanian Tea w/ Milk</title><link>https://based.cooking/tanzania-tea-with-milk/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://based.cooking/tanzania-tea-with-milk/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://based.cooking/pix/tanzania-tea-with-milk-01.webp" alt="tea-n-milk">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is a very traditional simple beverage from Tanzania, a country in East Africa. While I stayed there in Mwanza and Dar es Salaam, they
would always have this option for breakfast (or in general).&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>â²ï¸ Prep time: 5-10 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ðŸ³ Cook time: 3-8 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ðŸ½ï¸ Servings: 1&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Black Ceylon Tea (Preferably, you want a dark, herbal flavor from your tea. I have some from Dar es Salaam,
but when I tried researching, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t find out what kind of tea it is. No, they didn&amp;rsquo;t list the ingredients on
the box lol)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Milk/Sweet Cream&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Sweetener (Sugar, Syrup, Monk Fruit extract, etc.) (optional, but recommended)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://based.cooking/pix/tanzania-tea-with-milk-02.webp" alt="tea">&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Bring some hot water to boil and seep the tea. Depending on how strong you like it, you can do this for up to 10 min at most.
Be warned; typically black teas are very strong.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>When done seeping, add in the milk (or cream).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Sweeten to taste. Remember you can always add more if there isn&amp;rsquo;t enough.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Chicken Biscuit Potpie Recipe</title><link>https://based.cooking/chicken-biscuit-potpie/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://based.cooking/chicken-biscuit-potpie/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>1-2/3 cups frozen mixed vegetables, thawed&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1-1/2 cups cubed cooked chicken&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 can (10-3/4 ounces) condensed cream of chicken soup, undiluted&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/4 teaspoon dried thyme&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 cup biscuit/baking mix&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/2 cup whole milk&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 large egg&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Preheat oven to 400Â°F (200Â°C). In a large bowl, combine the vegetables, chicken, soup and thyme. Pour into an ungreased deep-dish 9-in. pie plate. Combine the biscuit mix, milk and egg; spoon over chicken mixture.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Bake until topping is golden brown and toothpick inserted in the center comes out clean, 25-30 minutes.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item></channel></rss>