<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Based Cooking</title><link>https://based.cooking/tags/mutton/</link><description>Recent content in mutton on Based Cooking</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://based.cooking/tags/mutton/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Lamb Biriyani</title><link>https://based.cooking/lamb-biriyani/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://based.cooking/lamb-biriyani/</guid><description>&lt;p>This recipe makes an Southern Indian (Tamil) style Lamb biriyani that has been adapted to a more western audience (aka a bit less spicy)
and can be made with either Lamb or Mutton. Best served with a sauce such as an &lt;a href="https://based.cooking/onion-raitha">onion raitha&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://based.cooking/pix/lamb-biriyani.webp" alt="Lamb Biriyani">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A plated rendering of the dish, made with Mutton. Makes a really hearty ,meaty and delicious dish. The dishes uses a rice to meat ratio of 2:3.
PS: the biriyani tastes better the longer it&amp;rsquo;s allowed to soak in it&amp;rsquo;s flavour after cooking.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>â²ï¸ Prep time: 30 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ðŸ³ Cook time: 1 hr 15 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ðŸ½ï¸ Servings: 4&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>4-5 pods of Cardamom&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2-3 Bay leaves&lt;/li>
&lt;li>3-4 Cinnamon Sticks&lt;/li>
&lt;li>8 Cloves&lt;/li>
&lt;li>400gm Basmati Rice&lt;/li>
&lt;li>600gm Mutton / Lamb (Boneless)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 Onions (Preferably Red)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 Tomatoes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 Green chilli (Optional)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>10 Garlic pearls&lt;/li>
&lt;li>5cm piece of Ginger&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/2 Tbsp of &lt;a href="https://based.cooking/garam-masala">Garam Masala&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 Tbsp of Chilli Powder or Hungarian Smoked Paprika&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Juice of 1/2 Lemon or 1 tsp of Vinegar&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Dash of Tumeric Powder&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Dash of Curry Powder&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 Sprig of Mint / Coriander (Garnish)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Wash the rice till the water turns clear and let the rice soak for at least 30 mins.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Chop the tomatoes down into tiny cubes and the onions into julienne slices. Grind the ginger and garlic into a paste.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>For the green chilli slice it midway to maintain it in one piece.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>In a big pot, Add 30 ml of neutral oil and toast the spices for 30 sec on medium heat.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add the onions and saute for around 3 min.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add the tomatoes, ginger and garlic paste and saute for another 3 min.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add the mutton/ lamb and 2 cups (500ml) of water. Add one Tbsp of salt.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Turn the heat up to high and add the green chilli, turmeric powder, chilli powder and 2 Tbsp of salt and let the mutton cook for about 40 -50 min.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Ensure that the pot does not run out of water and top up with more if required.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add about 2 cups of water or to about 800 gm of water in the pot while accounting for water left in the pot (1:2 ratio of rice to water).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Once boiling again, Add the rice, Garam Masala and Lemon juice / Vinegar to the pot.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Once 80% of the standing water has evaporated, Turn to the heat down to as low as possible and check the salt and spice levels and add more as required.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Now with a lid on, let the pot simmer for another 10 mins.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Serve with onion raitha and boiled Eggs and Garnish with coriander or mint sprigs. Enjoy!&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item></channel></rss>