<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Based Cooking</title><link>https://based.cooking/tags/spice/</link><description>Recent content in spice on Based Cooking</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://based.cooking/tags/spice/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Garam Masala</title><link>https://based.cooking/garam-masala/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://based.cooking/garam-masala/</guid><description>&lt;p>A spice mixture for most Indian dishes&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>4 Green Cardamom&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 Black Cardamom&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 tbsp Coriander&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 Cloves&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 tbsp Cumin&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 tbsp Fennel seeds&lt;/li>
&lt;li>5/6 Bayleaf&lt;/li>
&lt;li>5/6 Black pepper pods&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 Star anise (Optional)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Mace (Optional): Mace is a dried flower originating from the Nutmeg plant. Use no more than 3 strands of this flower.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Star anise and Mace are normally not added to Garam masala. They are added specially if someone is making &lt;a href="https://based.cooking/lamb-biriyani">Biriyani&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cloves will make the masala really hot. So make sure to add only as much as you want to eat.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Too much Mace makes the masala quite bitter. So make sure you do not add more than what has been recommended. The amount of other spices can be changed according to taste.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Wash all the dry spices really well.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>If you live in a place which is very sunny, sun dry your washed spices for about 1 day. If not then on a frying pan with a heavy bottom, place all the spices and dry roast them until aromatic.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cool the dry spices and put them into a mixer. Mix thoroughly.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Sieve the powder and add the larger pieces into the mixer once again and mix it again until everything turns into a fine powder. This step might need to be repeated a few times.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The resulting mixture is garam masala. Store it in airtight glass jars.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>You can store this mixture for about 2/3 months in a cool dry place.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item></channel></rss>